

SAMUEL FERNANDO PANJAITAN, S.KOM.

Padangsidimpuan, 25 May 1999 23 years old – Single – Christian Height 180 cm; Weight 55 kg



samuelfrnando@gmail.com https://www.linkedin.com/samuelfp

Inspeksi Pam Street No. 6, West Cakung, East Jakarta

Work Experiences

IT Business Analyst

Uniair Indotama Cargo, PT. | 16 February 2022 – Present

- Worked closely with product owners, UI/UX designer and Developers to ensure that our products are developed in accordance with the company's roadmap.
- Analyzed systems and mapped business processes to identify gaps and potential for improvements.
- Worked to fully understand the customer data and ensured that the data was utilized to make advantageous changes.
- Manage Master Data and presenting precise and structured reports.
- Monitor & operate WMS system (eComm+) and Customs PLB Inventory.
- Processing BC 16/BC 28 Lazada and Importir.org data into BC templates.

IT Support Technician

Uniair Indotama Cargo, PT. | 16 February 2022 – Present

- Provided complete IT technical support services and assisted global management teams to ensure efficient business processes.
- Conduct Proof of Concept (POC) on Access Point vendors (ARUBA, UBIQUITI, SUNDRAY, RUCKUS) to be used at Uniair PLB.
- Assembling Mikrotik networks and data cables, setup using Winbox.
- Update the operating system or applications regularly, Perform data Backup, Repairing damaged user computers and other hardwares.

IT Quality Assurance

Store2Go | 16 February 2022 – 16 April 2022

- Test the product (Store2Go App) and identify any bugs or errors.
- Create required documents, drafts, with standard QA procedure.
- Ensure that the products and applications designed are of good quality.

Licenses and Certifications

- EF SET English Certificate 82/100 (C2 Proficient) (29 December 2021).
- Dicoding: Building a Mobile Backend Using Kotlin (17 September 2020).
- RH 124: Red Hat Enterprise Linux System Administration I (16 January 2020)
- Dicoding: Class Learn to Create Android Applications for Beginners (18 November 2019).
- Alcatel-Lucent Enterprise Geek Battle Scholarship 2019 Basic Programming (18 November 2019).

Summary

I am a Bachelor of Computer: Informatics Engineering. I am 23 years old. My concentration in college is mobile and web. I am equipped with software programming education and can work in the IT field, related to data processing. My most recent experience is working as an IT Business Analyst as well as IT Support Technician. This makes me more trained to do multitasking.

Education

BACHELOR IN COMPUTER: INFORMATICS ENGINEERING - STMIK MIKROSKIL MEDAN (11 September 2017 - 25 July 2021). GPA 3.47 / 4.00

Achievement

The 3rd Rank in Competition Information Technology Mobile at STMIK Mikroskil Medan (11 January 2020).

Sample Project Experience

MEDANHUB: Mobile-Based Information Retrieval System Implementation on Society Reports Application in Medan City with Elasticsearch (13 August 2020 - 25 July 2021).

Hard Skills

- Administration (Microsoft Office).
- UI Design (Figma, Adobe XD).
- UML Diagrams (Visio, Lucidchart).
- Data Analysis (Postman, Kibana).
- Web Design (HTML and CSS).
- Programming (C#, Python, Kotlin).

